Konstantin Orlov

orlovkn.job@gmail.com | LinkedIn

Back End Developer

10+ years of experience as a back end web developer with a focus on creating websites and different customer services. During this time I've been creating more than 200 websites. I've been working with PHP since 2008 and have experience with Python, Java, and Android mobile development. Comfortable working remotely and know how to stay organized and how to work in a remote team. Love to learn new things, and pick up on new concepts fast, especially in a hands-on environment. My goal is to find a full-time position (remote or relocating) in a European company and be a great extension for your team.

Technical Skills

PHP | OOP, SOLID, Design Patterns, Clean Code | Symfony | Python | Django | Rest API | SOAP | PHPUnit | AWS | MySQL, MariaDB | PostgreSQL | MongoDB | Redis | Docker | RabbitMQ | Sphinx | Git | WordPress | Flask | VueJS | Slim | WebPack | HTML | CSS | jQuery | Composer | Scrum | Linux | JavaScript

Work Experience

Back End Developer

RT Labs Aug 2020 - Present

Participated in development of **SAAS** platform for creating ~200-250k government websites. Developed a **REST API** module for communication between base platform and websites. Developed service for creating patches and central updating websites and parts for the main controller.

- created elements and pages of base websites
- worked in a team with remote coworkers: developers, analytics, and designers

Back End Developer

WebWay May 2017 - Aug 2020

Created a website for one of the biggest insurance companies.

- **25+ calculators** and forms to buy a new policy, to send a report, or to ask some questions
- an analytical system with reports, graphics, and filters
- connections with different services (SOAP and REST), payment systems, receipt printing system

Website for one of the famous business coaches in Russia.

- website with possibility to choose and order physical or digital content (books, DVD, MP3, etc)
- **personal cabinet** for customers
- ticket system for events when you can choose the cost of your ticket, buy and print it

Back End Developer

Individ Aug 2016 - May 2017

My main focus was on the Bitrix framework. I was responsible for the development of new projects and technical support of current projects.

- created a website for a chain of federal medicine clinics
- **e-store** for a big tech company with many pages, services, and connections
- technical support of current projects

Back End Developer

NetCat Mar 2013 - Aug 2016

For this company, I worked as a **tech writer** and as a developer. For this company I:

- rewrote all official documentation for developers and users and created 30+ videos
- created module «Bills» for the main product of the company
- tested components of the system
- communicated with other remote developers
- performed technical support of other developers

Full Stack Developer

The South Urals Chamber Of Commerce And Industry

Feb 2010 - Mar 2013

My main role is the **development and support** of the company's main **website** and support services. Communicated with the company's customers and created websites for them.

- finished courses as a specialist with creating security tokens
- worked as a **coach** and taught people how to work on auction platforms

Full Stack Developer

Web Group «W» Nov 2008 - Feb 2010

Created a **social-network** for the builder's community, a **portal for a regional city** with different services. At this company I was responsible for:

- development of new projects
- technical support of current projects
- review code to increase the code quality and work with other developers

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science (2002 — 2007) Russian Free University